<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-conflict-development on Dr. Martin Ottmann</title>
    <link>/tags/post-conflict-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-conflict-development on Dr. Martin Ottmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/post-conflict-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizens in Peace Processes</title>
      <link>/project/micro-level-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/micro-level-peace/</guid>
      <description>Ordinary citizens typically bear the brunt of the destruction and violence in civil wars. At the same time, their engagement in and acceptance of peace processes is often a crucial ingredient for sustainable peace, while their lives continue to be shaped by the legacies of war long after weapons have fallen silent. Despite the important roles citizens play in waging war and making peace, much of what we know about peace processes in civil wars centers on the interests of elite actors and the groups that they lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Zones in Port-au-Prince</title>
      <link>/project/security-zones-and-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/security-zones-and-development/</guid>
      <description>The changing UN presence in Haiti opens up a window of opportunity to explore the social geography of this post-disaster country. After the withdrawal of MINUSTAH in April 2017, the UN has established a smaller peace mission, the United Nations Mission for Justice Support in Haiti (MINUJUSTH). The mission’s leadership is currently reviewing the specific delimitation of security zones, with the objective to shrink the yellow zone to a smaller, more targeted area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on &#39;Micro-Level Perspectives on Peace&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/micro-level-peace-birmingham-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/micro-level-peace-birmingham-workshop/</guid>
      <description>How can peace best be promoted following civil war? The transition from violent internal conflict to peace arguably is one of the most difficult challenges a society can face. Although a small number of countries has managed to prevent renewed civil war, others are often caught in &amp;lsquo;conflict traps&amp;rsquo;. Of those countries that have managed to prevent a relapse into full-scale war, many are characterized by high violent crime rates, illicit economies, corruption, violent protests, or simmering non-state conflicts between armed militias in the periphery, rendering the &amp;lsquo;quality&amp;rsquo; of the post-conflict peace poor, at best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Power-Sharing</title>
      <link>/project/peps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/peps/</guid>
      <description>How does power-sharing affect resource allocation between elites and constituencies in post-conflict situations? The question if and how power-sharing arrangements between a state government and former rebel groups actually change the distribution and exercise of political power in a post-conflict situation is rarely investigated. In this project, we argue that the type of power-sharing affects sub-national resource allocation patterns. Power-sharing provides an opportunity for former conflict actors to access state resources and distribute those resources strategically to their constituencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>