<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power-sharing on Dr. Martin Ottmann</title>
    <link>/tags/power-sharing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power-sharing on Dr. Martin Ottmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/power-sharing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Power-Sharing</title>
      <link>/project/peps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/peps/</guid>
      <description>How does power-sharing affect resource allocation between elites and constituencies in post-conflict situations? The question if and how power-sharing arrangements between a state government and former rebel groups actually change the distribution and exercise of political power in a post-conflict situation is rarely investigated. In this project, we argue that the type of power-sharing affects sub-national resource allocation patterns. Power-sharing provides an opportunity for former conflict actors to access state resources and distribute those resources strategically to their constituencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power-Sharing Event Dataset (PSED)</title>
      <link>/project/psed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/psed/</guid>
      <description>The Power-Sharing Event Dataset (PSED) contains information on the promises and practices of power-sharing between governments and rebels for a five-year period after the conclusion of a peace agreement (unless violence recurred earlier). The main features of this dataset are the specific focus on government-rebel dyads during post-conflict periods, an exact temporal mapping of implemented or abolished power-sharing events, and detailed descriptions for each power-sharing arrangement put into practice. This codebook describes the definitions of core concepts and operationalization of variables in this data collection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>