<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Martin Ottmann on Dr. Martin Ottmann</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr. Martin Ottmann on Dr. Martin Ottmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Causal Inference</title>
      <link>/teaching/inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/inference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Causality plays an essential role in the social sciences whenever we wish to find out whether a particular intervention actually changes an outcome of interest. However, causality is difficult to study. It has long been known in the social sciences that correlation does not imply causation. Especially when working with observational data, researchers miss crucial information for making causal interpretations of statistical associations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This module explores research designs and modern methods of causal inference for statistical research. This module will explore under which circumstances and subject to which assumptions, researchers can interpret estimated associations as causal with substantially higher confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst other things, the module will explore theories of causality and the potential outcome framework; the fundamental problem of causal inference and its possible solutions; ‘selection on observables’ identification strategies; and selection on unobservables’ identification strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A module handbook and course material will be made available in April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro-Level Perspectives on Peace</title>
      <link>/project/micro-level-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/micro-level-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While macro-level analyses have greatly contributed to our understanding of post-conflict peacebuilding, a macro-only approach entails serious shortcomings. These include a potential mismatch between theoretical mechanisms and empirical data, and a failure to take into account the attitudes of citizens towards peace, problems that may mean only superficially relevant knowledge is produced for practitioners. Addressing this issue, we take up the idea of the &amp;lsquo;micro-level&amp;rsquo; as a conceptual and empirical distinction that breaks up the territorial state or dyads as levels of analysis in favor of lower-level units of analysis, such as individuals, sub-groups, or geographical regions. Using this concept, we argue that it is particularly worthwhile to study micro-level perspectives on peace in four interconnected areas that are particularly relevant in conflict-affected states: security, political access, rule of law, and economic development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These micro-level perspectives on peace will be explored in a workshop series jointly organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carolinehartzell.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Caroline Hartzell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://felixhaass.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Felix Haass&lt;/a&gt;, and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Design, Practice and Ethics</title>
      <link>/teaching/rdpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/rdpe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The module will introduce students to the concepts and varieties of social science research designs. Research design consists of choices necessary to transform a research question into actual research. These choices relate to strategies and modes of case selection, data collection and modes of analysis, and they pertain equally to qualitative, quantitative and mixed-methods studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every research question can be elaborated in different ways; none of these will be ideal in all respects, so that design choices have implications in terms of costs and benefits. The module will discuss these implications, considering the kinds of conclusions that can reliably be drawn from the different kinds of evidence produced by different designs. Key design features such as groups, timing and measurement will be introduced and illustrated through a range of research designs including experimental and quasi-experimental, case study design and longitudinal design. Design elements will be linked into the full cycle of research activity, from knowledge synthesis through to policy or practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A module handbook and course material will be made available in November 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Zones and Development</title>
      <link>/project/security-zones-and-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/security-zones-and-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every international intervention comes with its own security regulations, which contribute in turn to structure the political geography of the intervention, delimiting areas of interaction between interveners and local population and shaping the political economy of intervention. We argue that these security regulations can have a substantial impact on the political and economic development of post-conflict/post-disaster countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will commence in September 2019 in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/schools/government-society/departments/international-development/staff/profiles/lemay-hebert-nicolas.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nicolas Lemay-Hébert&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/schools/government-society/departments/international-development/staff/profiles/hudson-david.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;David Hudson&lt;/a&gt;. Seed funding has been provided under the &amp;lsquo;Resilient Cities&amp;rsquo; theme of the University of Birmingham&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/research/global-goals/igi/index.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Institute for Global Innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on &#39;Micro-Level Perspectives on Peace&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/micro-level-peace-birmingham-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/micro-level-peace-birmingham-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can peace best be promoted following civil war? The transition from violent internal conflict to peace arguably is one of the most difficult challenges a society can face. Although a small number of countries has managed to prevent renewed civil war, others are often caught in &amp;lsquo;conflict traps&amp;rsquo;. Of those countries that have managed to prevent a relapse into full-scale war, many are characterized by high violent crime rates, illicit economies, corruption, violent protests, or simmering non-state conflicts between armed militias in the periphery, rendering the &amp;lsquo;quality&amp;rsquo; of the post-conflict peace poor, at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carolinehartzell.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Caroline Hartzell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://felixhaass.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Felix Haass&lt;/a&gt;, and I will explore the quality of post-war peace in a series of workshops. The firstwill take place in September at the University of Birmingham. We have been lucky to secure the participation of a number of scholars working on post-conflict peace as, for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kristinbakke.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kristin Bakke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabinecarey.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sabine Carey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jessicamaves.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jessica Maves Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/schools/government-society/departments/international-development/staff/profiles/dasandi-niheer.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Niheer Dasandi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.egsh.eur.nl/people/s-m-murshed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mansoob Murshed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millimaylake.weebly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Milli Lake&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://alexandrahartman.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alex Hartman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of our workshops is the notion of adopting a micro-level perspective on post-conflict peace. While macro-level analyses have greatly contributed to our understanding of post-conflict peacebuilding, a macro-only approach entails serious shortcomings. These include a potential mismatch between theoretical mechanisms and empirical data, and a failure to take into account the attitudes of citizens towards peace, problems that may mean only superficially relevant knowledge is produced for practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing these issue, we take up the idea of the “micro-level” as a conceptual and empirical distinction that breaks up the territorial state or dyads as levels of analysis in favor of lower-level units of analysis, such as individuals, sub-groups, or geographical regions. We argue that it is particularly worthwhile to study micro-level perspectives on peace in four interconnected areas that are particularly relevant in conflict-affected states: security, political access, rule of law, and economic development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Peace Trickle Down? Micro-Level Evidence from Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/afropeps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/afropeps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Power-Sharing</title>
      <link>/project/peps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/peps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does power-sharing affect resource allocation between elites and constituencies in post-conflict situations? The question if and how power-sharing arrangements between a state government and former rebel groups actually change the distribution and exercise of political power in a post-conflict situation is rarely investigated. In this project, we argue that the type of power-sharing affects sub-national resource allocation patterns. Power-sharing provides an opportunity for former conflict actors to access state resources and distribute those resources strategically to their constituencies. Ultimately, this implies that power-sharing is less a tool for transforming political power (and thus addressing the root causes of social conflict), but an instrument that institutionalizes patronage opportunities. The project relies on the combination of quantitative and qualitative methods to substantiate these hypotheses: We first use statistical geo-spatial methods in order to investigate power-sharing as mechanism for sub-national resource redistribution to core constituencies. This analysis will make use of global data on post-conflict situations between 1992 and 2010. Central to this effort will be the creation of a novel dataset, the Geographical Dimensions of Power-Sharing Dataset (GDPS) which geo-locates the constituencies of all government and rebels in post-conflict situations. In a second step, we will conduct qualitative within-case analyses and in-depth process tracing of two post-conflict situations: Liberia and the Indonesian province of Aceh. This qualitative analysis will be based on field research in each post-conflict situation to better understand causal processes and scope conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is funded by a research grant of the German Research Foundation. Collaborators are Andreas Mehler and Felix Haass.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Compromised Peace? The Effect of Power-Sharing Arrangements on Post-War Violence</title>
      <link>/publication/post-war-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/post-war-violence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government-Rebel Relations in the Wake of Power-Sharing Peace Agreements</title>
      <link>/publication/power-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/power-relations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previous Courses</title>
      <link>/teaching/previous-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/previous-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previous courses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-Conflict Reconstruction and Development (MA, University of Birmingham, Spring 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conflict in Developing Countries (MA, University of Birmingham, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebel Governance in Civil Wars (BA, University of Hamburg, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power-Sharing in Post-Conflict Situations (BA, University of Hamburg, 2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Security (BA, University of Nottingham, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding Global Politics (BA, University of Nottingham, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems in Global Politics (BA, University of Nottingham, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profits from Peace: The Political Economy of Power-Sharing and Corruption</title>
      <link>/publication/profits-from-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/profits-from-peace/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebel Constituencies and Rebel Violence Against Civilians in Civil Conflicts</title>
      <link>/publication/vac-and-constituencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/vac-and-constituencies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power-Sharing Event Dataset (PSED): A New Dataset on the Promises and Practices of Power-Sharing in Post-Conflict Countries</title>
      <link>/publication/psed-data-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/psed-data-feature/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power-Sharing Event Dataset (PSED)</title>
      <link>/project/psed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/psed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Power-Sharing Event Dataset (PSED) contains information on the promises and practices of power-sharing between governments and rebels for a five-year period after the conclusion of a peace agreement (unless violence recurred earlier). The main features of this dataset are the specific focus on government-rebel dyads during post-conflict periods, an exact temporal mapping of implemented or abolished power-sharing events, and detailed descriptions for each power-sharing arrangement put into practice. This codebook describes the definitions of core concepts and operationalization of variables in this data collection. It also presents the PSED coding procedure. An explanation of the theoretical impetus behind the PSED as well as an in-depth discussion of its concepts can be found in the PSED data feature in Conflict Management and Peace Science (Ottmann and Vüllers 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was funded by a research grant of the German Research Foundation. Collaborators are Andreas Mehler and Johannes Vüllers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
